Strange things burned, yes, so
the question is whether in the stages of
the formless realm I still
have the observer in mind, the future,
how I dissolve the space of the future,
how consciousness expands. So
the answer is connected to the air conditioning,
always the mental state of the desire
realm.
There, the mind always goes back and forth
between the bad pop song in the
supermarket and the fantastic "What"
line by Jimi Hendrix.
During the conversion, a whole lifetime, my
whole life, it's been about the realm of desire,
even when a mind
perceives things, or when it
delves so deeply to perceive the details of the song
or the kiss. When you
then begin form meditation,
you still have these two primitive mental
states, noticing the music in the
supermarket and going a little
deeper in the
desire realm. It's not like
you're suddenly like that in the supermarket
when you then begin the form realms.
Actually, there are three steps that I have
n't actually told you about. Do
you use these?  Two states of mind to
make the transition:
the form state of the desire
realm to the form state of the realm of form.
You use "notice" and "
verify" in Sanskrit, Vitara.
Developers: the first Vitara is simply
noticing what's loose in your life. With
Sarah, delve a little deeper.
Now, when you bring the state of mind from the desire realm to the form
realm, you use
these two for about the next half
hour. Why? Because the weather
still hears the air conditioning. You notice the
noise, like Zara, we hear the heartbeat.
This is a little more subtle, and this will be
crucial. I want her to be there. I ca
n't use
the air conditioning anymore. It was
always there to go to work on time.
They're not that cool. I want more silence.
And then you go into the
sound of the heart.
After they've made the transition, the
main state of mind is again
very deep in this heartbeat, and you
have very little awareness of the air
conditioning. You've left it behind.
Each of these stages has something
you reject, something you deserve.  I
prefer the calm scent of my
heart, and I now leave the
air conditioner behind. The weather says goodbye
to the air conditioner, and
Sarah greets the heart. I
like this peace.
And now the answer to your question:
when you make the transition from the
first stage in form realm to the second
stage in form realm, there is the feeling that
I am now the heartbeat. There is
no observer of the heartbeat anymore;
you are the heartbeat. So,
if we say that Vita and Dzaka
exist in the first level, and we
use Vitara, we are only looking back at the
air conditioner and saying that this
is not nice. Sarah enjoys
this new peace. But when you move from the
first form, from the first stage of the
right to the second, you let go of
both, and the feeling, the sensation,
is that I am my heartbeat. Okay, no one
can hear you; there is no microphone.
In the next levels, I watch my mind
as my mind expands in space. The
feeling is not that you are
observing that  The feeling is, I'm in
these things. You only lose this
feeling of being an observer on the
first stage of being the richest; from then on,
you are truly there.